PROFILE

I'm a data specialist with experience in data analysis, data visualization, and programming. I thrive in environments that allow me to take on the challenge of building solutions to solve inefficient processes and gather business intelligence that reveals challenges and guide business success.

CONTACT

www.linkedin.com/in/amahmartin

 \oplus www.amahmartin.me

www.github.com/ammartin8

SKILLS

Languages

+ Python

+ CSS3

+ SQL

+ iQuery

+ JavaScript

+ M query

+ HTML5 + PySpark + DAX

Databases

+ SQLite

+ IBM Db2 on Cloud

+ PostgreSQL

+ Oracle

Tools & Systems

+ Microsoft Excel

+ SAS + Microsoft Power BI + React JS

+ Visual Studio Code + Figma

+ Jupyter Notebook

+ Git

+ GitHub

+ NPM

+ Bootstrap

+ Anaconda

Framework + REST APIs

+ Tableau

+ Toad Data Point &

+ Miro

Oracle

Query + CRM

+ Azure DevOps

Storefront

Interpersonal Skills

+ Data Analysis

+ Automation

+ Microsoft Databricks + Power

+ Teamwork

+ Quality Assurance

+ Problem Solving

Technical Writing

+ Automation + Teamwork

+ Agile Methodology

+ Problem Solving + Relationship

+ Data Stewardship

+ Customer

Building + Project

Service + Troubleshooting

Management + Business Requirements Translation

Hobbies Photography

Programming

Digital Art Gaming

AMAH MARTIN

DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL

EDUCATION

Microsoft, Remote

Certified in Azure Data Fundamentals

December 2021

IBM. Remote

Certificate of Completion

August 2021 - March 2022

Python for Data Science, SQL for Data Science,

Data Engineering Basics for Everyone, Advance SQL for Data Engineers

Code Louisville Program, Louisville, KY

Certificate of Completion in Front End & Back End Development May 2019 - April 2020

Jefferson Community & Technical College, Louisville, KY

Certificate in Programming

August 2019 – April 2020

University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY Master of Public Health

August 2014 - May 2016

University of Louisville, Louisville, KY Chemistry, B.A.

August 2008 - May 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data and Reporting Professional

Humana, Louisville, KY

March 2021 – Present

- Completed 366+ hours of work items for the Marketing Analytics and Data team in a 4-month period in both an accurate and efficient manner that resulted in the success of completing business partner's goals and objectives
- Automated several Excel reports through the use of Power BI, SQL, and Python programming resulting increase productivity and saved 3+ hours of manual Excel work
- · Quickly adapted to an Agile work environment in a short period of time
- Maintain relationships with stakeholders in order to translate business requirements into technical requirements
- Provided streamlined reporting and analytics data to senior leadership for business intelligence (BI) visualizations to quickly identify growth areas and areas of opportunity.

Advance Data Analytics Immersive Fellow

General Assembly, Louisville, KY

March 2021 – May 2021

- Completed 400+ hours of full-time remote learning with a focus in analyzing real world datasets using Excel, PostgreSQL, Tableau, and Python.
- Developed skills in data wrangling, descriptive analysis, and communication of data to a non-technical audience.
- Evaluated over 250,000 rows of data and translated data into useful visualizations and communicated recommendations to prevent traffic collisions using Excel and Tableau.

Epidemiologist | Quality Assurance Analyst

Cabinet for Health and Family Services, Frankfort, KY

June 2017 - March 2021

- Automated processes including an entire Vital Statistics Annual Report which increased productivity on tasks by up to 88%.
- Responded to 210+ data requests over a 3-year period resulting in successful completion of client's organizational goals and objectives.
- Translated data into business intelligence for IT staff solving data quality assurance challenges and improving data quality inefficiency for clients and staff.
- Received awards by senior leadership for excellent work ethic and project accomplishments.

Graduate Research Fellow | Public Health Intern

University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY

January 2015 - May 2016

- Conducted a qualitative analysis which resulted receiving an estimate \$1,000 grant used to improve health outcomes in a rural hospital in Zimbabwe.
- Developed a logistic regression model identifying of risk factors that contribute to work place injuries in the aquaculture industry using SAS, Excel, & GIS.